<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ShiddyIO</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://shiddy.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://shiddy.io/</id><updated>2024-11-20T12:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Dotfile Management &amp; Git Tricks</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/dotfile-management-git-tricks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-11-20T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Shiddy</name></author><id>tag:shiddy.io,2024-11-20:/dotfile-management-git-tricks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;style&gt;
mark{
    background: linear-gradient(to right, #6666ff, #0099ff , #00ff00, #ff3399, #6666ff);
    -webkit-background-clip: text;
    background-clip: text;
    color: transparent;
    animation: rainbow_animation 6s ease-in-out infinite;
    background-size: 400% 100%;
}

@keyframes rainbow_animation {
    0%,100% {
        background-position: 0 0;
    }

    50% {
        background-position: 100% 0;
    }
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Preamble"&gt;Preamble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#GNU-Stow"&gt;GNU-Stow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#TheIdea"&gt;The Idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Tangent-Time"&gt;Tangent Time!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Managing-Dotfiles"&gt;Managing Dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#AmuseBouche"&gt;Amuse Bouche, Repo Specific Git …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;style&gt;
mark{
    background: linear-gradient(to right, #6666ff, #0099ff , #00ff00, #ff3399, #6666ff);
    -webkit-background-clip: text;
    background-clip: text;
    color: transparent;
    animation: rainbow_animation 6s ease-in-out infinite;
    background-size: 400% 100%;
}

@keyframes rainbow_animation {
    0%,100% {
        background-position: 0 0;
    }

    50% {
        background-position: 100% 0;
    }
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Preamble"&gt;Preamble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#GNU-Stow"&gt;GNU-Stow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#TheIdea"&gt;The Idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Tangent-Time"&gt;Tangent Time!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Managing-Dotfiles"&gt;Managing Dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#AmuseBouche"&gt;Amuse Bouche, Repo Specific Git Configs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a id="Preamble"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Preamble&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/stow/"&gt;GNU STOW&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/"&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; to manage &lt;a href="https://github.com/shiddy/dot"&gt;my dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;. This means that all I have to do on a new machine is access my git repo, install stow, and pitter patter - let's get att'er. After many years of manually managing these files, using different migration tools, and writing a tool myself, I can confidently say that stow is the best solution I've used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The readme on my dotfiles should be easy enough to follow, but &lt;mark style="padding-top:0;"&gt;the shiddy blog&lt;/mark&gt; is where I take the time to talk through some of the more interesting bits, updating your files, security considerations, and if you ask nicely some useful quality of life pieces. Join me will you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="GNU-Stow"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;GNU-Stow&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNU Stow is a really nice piece of software that does not get enough attention. It's also getting up there in years, &lt;a href="https://git.savannah.gnu.org/cgit/stow.git/commit/?id=1b3b46907af7f23032645f14c27778cf77eae4dd"&gt;with its initial release in 2001&lt;/a&gt; it's had enough eyes on it that it will work for my use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic premise is that you can set up a slightly strange directory structure, call &lt;code&gt;stow&lt;/code&gt; within the root of that directory and stow will create symlinks that the rest of your system will see and treat as regular files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works quite well within git, where we can archive our stow configuration, but also because our configuration files are symlinks, whenever we change any of our configuration files (since they are symlinks), we can see all the changes as git changes natively and commit them without extra fuss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="TheIdea"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Idea&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic premise is that we want to create our directory with paths that reflect the paths to our configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$HOME/.zshrc =&amp;gt; $HOME/DOTFILEREPO/zsh/.zshrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a id="Tangent-Time"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tangent time!&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to start using linux around Canonical's Precise Pangolin (12.04) release. If you ask me it was the perfect time to get serious because I was so late to the game. A ton of the bullshit was solved by smarter people than me. I could reasonably start learning with things that were in a functional state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of my future co-workers and co-horts would wax on about the nightmarish ages of old, and how easy I had it in comparison. Some of the more notable examples:
* Buying a new laptop after fighting with ndiswrapper and a random broadcom nic longer than the cost of hours lost to it not working.
* Trying to quit cigarettes when the company needed you to deploy iptables before firewalld existed.
* wicd and iwlconfig for setting up wireless devices before NetworkManager, and only having one laptop without an ethernet port.
* Running an isolinux memdisk kernel to install because many BIOSes didn't support usb booting, and praying that the myriad of tunables to whatever incantation your conputer's firmware would be accepted before el torito cd extensions.
* Buying an nvidia graphics card and having to have a seperate windows machine to install the driver on, copying the needed files back to linux and running the "NVIDIA X Server Settings" gui to get a wildly inconsistent kernel interface to a busted driver so the nvidia module compilation would fail and you would have to spend weeks old manually compiled kernels waiting for upstream fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be fair, I rarely get to use SIMD as much as I'd like. I hardly get to use compiled languaged as much as I'd like. But I've never been told by the guy who made my operating system that I should be retroactively aborted for using an enumerable for a system call read. If that did happen I have a feeling I would probably just install windows and get a job in finance or something idk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I lost the plot in this tangent a bit, but my point is that there has never been a better time to be getting into computing. The only real problem at this point is the curation of quality content. There is a decent amount of amazing material, and a seemingly infinite amount of absolute slop. Honestly, one of the best skills in comp-sci is just being around and paying attention while things are happening. Then you at least know what things felt like when computers were a hundred times slower, and why opening a random program shouldn't take 40 seconds long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People in those positions don't often praise the progress we have made, we don't often tell the stories where a bunch of people got together and cleaned up an utter shit-fest and left us with a better strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of this, how many common places exist for executables?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;/bin
/sbin
/usr/bin
/usr/sbin
/usr/local/bin
macos has bin and sbin directories for homebrew and a few for [Cryptex](https://support.apple.com/guide/security/apple-security-research-device-seca7ff718d2/1/web/1)
random install dirs for things like node where they want you have to update your path after install
~/Downloads  that one time you downloaded an .exe from your work email that strangely did nothing but open the commandline for a second.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this list feels excessive... But don't get it twisted, &lt;strong&gt;at least&lt;/strong&gt; there is a known and defined place for executables. Until &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; recently, configuration files were an absolute shit-show. Everyone who made a program that would have user specific configs would put them wherever they could. You want to put all your user specific data, configs, and state in a place specific to the user? &lt;code&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt; is good enough. Then your &lt;code&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt; directory looked like an ADHD teen's bedroom and you had to just let it fester over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or... hear me out, you could just sweep all the clutter under the rug by hiding the files from your default file program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="eyebrows.gif" src="https://shiddy.io/images/eyebrows.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that sounds stupid, because it is. But the reason flags like &lt;code&gt;-a&lt;/code&gt; exist on &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt;, and some files are hidden by default is because it makes finding the random file in your home directory harder. Until the X11 Desktop Group &lt;a href="https://specifications.freedesktop.org/basedir-spec/latest/index.html"&gt;proposed a standard on base directories in 2003&lt;/a&gt; there was not a place other than random dotfiles in your home directory. It's one of the main reasons that we call our user configuration files dotfiles in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This standard means that we are able to move all our files to a directory where they belong, so long as the programs are written to respect the XDG standards (the number of which is growing pretty steadily)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see on their docs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;code&gt;$XDG_CONFIG_HOME&lt;/code&gt; defines the base directory relative to which user-specific configuration files should be stored. If &lt;code&gt;$XDG_CONFIG_HOME&lt;/code&gt; is either not set or empty, a default equal to &lt;code&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt;/.config should be used."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have a great reason for deviating from the default &lt;code&gt;$HOME/.config&lt;/code&gt; path so that is what I will use the rest of this article&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So cheers to you XDG Standard writers. Let's hope this becomes popular enough that people in the future don't even know what hidden files are, and we can add a new mitre attack group for gen alpha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a id="Managing-Dotfiles"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tangent Time Over, Managing Dotfiles&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to make a new repository in your version control software; Fill it with directories of the programs you want to manage the dotfiles for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth pointing out that since we are setting up our dotfiles to be managed to the XDG_CONFIG_HOME standard we can add a .config directory here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;dot
 |-nvim
 |--.config
 |-tmux
 |--.config
 |-zsh
 |--.config (* you will have do add a .zshenv &amp;#39;export ZDOTDIR=&amp;quot;$HOME/.config&amp;quot;&amp;#39;)
 |--.zshenv
 | ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we need to start moving our configs there. This works quite well if you are running on a new machine, lest you accidentally kill what you have in the process of copying things over...otherwise be careful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;once you have moved everything over your directories should be populated with some of your dotfiles. It should look something like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;dot
 |-nvim
 |--.config
 |---(imagine some LUA or something stupid)
 |-tmux
 |--.config
 |---.tmux.conf
 |-zsh
 |--.config
 |---.zshrc
 |--.zshenv
 | ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to use stow to link everything! The basic command looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;stow -d PATH/TO/YOUR/REPO -t ~ YOURPROGRAMNAME&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt; is the directory your stow should be running from, in this case we set it to the directory of our repo, variable expansion works fine btw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-t&lt;/code&gt; is the target where we want to write symlinks to, in our case I use &lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt; which means our home directory of our current user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;YOURPROGRAMNAME&lt;/code&gt; would refer to the directories that we created for each of our programs. &lt;code&gt;nvim&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; or whatever you specified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling really randy, you can also just make a shell script that has all these commands ready for a fresh install, or even a blog post so that you don't have to do that until you get to this part of the blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="ch"&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# I&amp;#39;m assuming you are using git, so I ignore .git and the current directory here, I assume you can change it if you need to.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;line&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;find&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-type&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;d&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-maxdepth&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;sed&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;s|.\/||&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;grep&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-v&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-e&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;.git&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-e&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;\.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;stow&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-d&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;pwd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-t&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;~&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$line&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can install everything with &lt;code&gt;/bin/bash whateveryounamethatthing.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can see any config changes you make with your version control, and updating it is as simple as committing your changes and fetching whatever changes you want on whatever machine you are using. Different branches can work for OS changes or local stack changes for me, but the sky is the limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and that's pretty much it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a id="AmuseBouche"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Multiple Git SSH configs on one machine&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for an adjacent idea that I want to treat you to... like a blog amuse bouche&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow I find myself with a many to many relationship between git accounts and git servers with different auth schemes. This is very annoying since you can't use the same ssh pub keys on multiple accounts, this is why git@github.com allows you to test auth to it without a tty and github does not have to do weird pathing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;also, did you know that you can get anyone's public keys off of github?
&lt;a href="https://github.com/theprimeagen.keys"&gt;The Primagen's Public RSA Keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See? This is an intentional design choice but can lead to some unintentional data loss. *The Primagen does not know that he has root access to my machines... yet* So it's not uncommon to generate and revoke keys often if you are being serious about security and what you put online... perhaps that's an indicator of something I'm working on, perhaps it's not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you find yourself in the same situation you might have some random directory need to use a different ssh key for authing to your git server, while also using a completely different key for another repo on the same computer, this is the section that helps you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that .git directory I ignored in my dotfiles before? that has all the information of what's happening to the files on your repo, local and remote. If you look at a "normal" repository, there is a &lt;code&gt;.git/config&lt;/code&gt; file that shows these connections to a local user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;[core]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;repositoryformatversion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;filemode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;bare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;logallrefupdates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;ignorecase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;precomposeunicode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;[remote &amp;quot;origin&amp;quot;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;git@github.com:idk/something.git&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;fetch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;+refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/origin/*&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;[branch &amp;quot;main&amp;quot;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;remote&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;origin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;merge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;refs/heads/main&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recall, we know that we have git@github.com as the remote user/host info in this file. So we need to configure the ssh connection information to something else. We can do so by adding a host to &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/config&lt;/code&gt; so that we can then edit the connection information in our repo's &lt;code&gt;.git/conffig&lt;/code&gt; and have it route somewhere else. That looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;# $HOME/.ssh/config
Host shiddy
    HostName github.com
    User git
    IdentityFile /Users/user/.ssh/your-private-key-for-this-user
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we are essentially saying is that we should make a fake host (in my case called shiddy) that should be handled differently. So now we can update our &lt;code&gt;.git/config&lt;/code&gt; file in our repo to use this fake host&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;[core]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;repositoryformatversion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;filemode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;bare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;logallrefupdates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;ignorecase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;precomposeunicode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;[remote &amp;quot;origin&amp;quot;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;git@shiddy:idk/something.git&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# NOTE THE DOMAIN CHANGE&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;fetch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;+refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/origin/*&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;[branch &amp;quot;main&amp;quot;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;remote&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;origin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;merge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;refs/heads/main&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will work all well and good, but also would mean that every commit you make will be for whatever your global git user is, which can be another data loss that you can run into committing to different git repos as same user. So we have one final change we should make to our local git config:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;[core]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;repositoryformatversion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;filemode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;bare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;logallrefupdates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;ignorecase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;precomposeunicode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;[remote &amp;quot;origin&amp;quot;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;git@personal-github:shiddy/dot.git&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;fetch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;+refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/origin/*&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;[branch &amp;quot;main&amp;quot;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;remote&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;origin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;merge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;refs/heads/main&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;[user] # This tells git to use the following user for git changes to all it manages in this .git repo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;shiddy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And would you guess, the changes to &lt;code&gt;.ssh/config&lt;/code&gt; are also dotfiles? So minding all of the ways you can passively leak information, you can add the &lt;code&gt;.ssh/config&lt;/code&gt; changes to your stow repo. I'll leave that as an exercise for the reader if you are so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Hopefully you learned something, and if you have anything to say I guess you can find my contact links at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK BYE |o･-･)ﾉ&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="Technical"></category><category term="Musings"></category></entry><entry><title>Some thoughts on Artificial Intelligence</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/some-thoughts-on-artificial-intelligence.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-01T12:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-08-01T12:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Shiddy</name></author><id>tag:shiddy.io,2023-08-01:/some-thoughts-on-artificial-intelligence.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://shiddy.io/images/gits_brain.jpg#headimg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;On the cusp of something&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear reader, If you are anything like me you are already thoroughly exhausted with everyone else's perspective on artificial intelligence. Everyone talking confidently is either pushing something, or has just as much insight on the subject as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I've spent too much of my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://shiddy.io/images/gits_brain.jpg#headimg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;On the cusp of something&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear reader, If you are anything like me you are already thoroughly exhausted with everyone else's perspective on artificial intelligence. Everyone talking confidently is either pushing something, or has just as much insight on the subject as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I've spent too much of my life listening to sad nerds peacocking to give any attention to this new shiny thing. Yet, it's undeniable that recent LLM developments mark a leap in technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE DISSONANCE!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some collection of my thoughts that are not sweeping societal BS everyone seems to love. I've broken them into different pages, they seem to read better as short little stories. These thoughts may be dumb, but they are at least mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://shiddy.io/dont-be-why-the-i-in-ai-is-always-lacking.html"&gt; Don't Be - Why the "I" in AI is always lacking. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;More Coming Soon, my fingers hurt&lt;/h4&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="Musings"></category></entry><entry><title>The Report to the Shareholders Q4 2022</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/the-report-to-the-shareholders-q4-2022.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-11-16T05:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-11-16T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Shiddy</name></author><id>tag:shiddy.io,2022-11-16:/the-report-to-the-shareholders-q4-2022.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Q4 2022 - Report to the Shareholders&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger warning: Depression, Self-Harm, and Suicide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That satisfaction of pretending to be the hero, assuming the decency of institutions, qualifying personal truths with a "hot take" warning, the vindication of being the smuggest corpse in the mass grave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to release these familiar …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Q4 2022 - Report to the Shareholders&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger warning: Depression, Self-Harm, and Suicide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That satisfaction of pretending to be the hero, assuming the decency of institutions, qualifying personal truths with a "hot take" warning, the vindication of being the smuggest corpse in the mass grave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to release these familiar feelings and keep finding myself hitting a wall. I've turned into one of the old dogs. I'm worried I am Okonkwo and I didn't spot the missionaries in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this all too macabre, too obtuse, too self-referential? I can't help but assume that any reader trying to inventory their current situation would stumble into something more tactful than this... Shit, If your attention has not faltered from these literary turds on this blog up to this point, I guess I owe you some thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;From Here on up, The Hills Don't Get Any Higher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been catching myself day-dreaming a lot as of late. Seems to me that whenever the weather changes and the day turns to night before you get to where you're going, my brain starts filling the empty space with pontification. The current track has to do with this bubble, a myth to me but perhaps familiar to some of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some businesses (Businesses hiring really smart people mind you) have been working with these machines you see. These machines are able to be linked together, they make more than the sum of their parts, they are used to formulate and solve problems outside your understanding. These things will be the only tool worth learning, a breaker in our technological evolution. There will be but a threshold, the before, the arcane, the analogue. Now we have the new, the sleek the digital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the bubble popped... oopsy woopsy ¯\&lt;em&gt;(ツ)&lt;/em&gt;/¯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;...But the Valleys Get Deeper and Deeper&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those playing the home game and are at a loss, I'm talking about the 90s ".com" bubble. I doubt that were I alive then I would have the wisdom to see through the hype. That I would be able to suss out that in spite of how impressive hardware is or may become, that these computers are just as paltry as any other tool when commoditized. The markets would correct, the business would follow suit. The time working as a html code monkey has run out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disregard for substance today... it's hard to take its measure. I have a strong conviction in my soul that Americans are currently on a similar trajectory as they were in the 90s. Here is a thought experiment: What is a "tech company" to you? I implore you to ask yourself earnestly. I've had the fortune of seeing more than one tech company to its conclusion while the getting was good, lining my pockets along the way. To be honest, I don't know how much I would call my work technical. I can frame my work in a lens to keep that from being an outright lie, but I won't pretend that it's convincing to even myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not so foolish as to think think that I will end up unscathed as our current bubble pops. I'm also not going to pretend that I am different than the Boomers in the 60s or the Gen-Xers in the 90s. I'm doing the same looking at a younger generation saying "Fuck you; got mine." Bluntly, my intent is to prove that I am a problem solver and a worthwhile person to have in one's corner. It feels more prudent than ever to play my hand well, and make myself useful as a mover and shaker. Not that any of these perspectives are new, or a substantive course correction from my norm, just worth expressing that if things do go to shit I'll be around with my ears and eyes open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Are you going to do something or just stand there and bleed?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't know how to point out the dialectic at play in my head as of late. I feel that I have (perhaps maladaptively) reinforced the position that I must always seek the path to better my condition. To take every interaction in my memory and try to wrangle it into a box labeled growth. I am the one who gallivants around making the big choices, min-maxing my kit, and ending on a pile of loot. Every option to be framed from the hero's perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that's cringe. It hurt to type. Fighting that perspective however, is more alien to me than I would like to admit. It all feels like a neurotic ultra-liberal fixation that might have motivated and sustained me when I was younger, but now rings increasingly hollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm far too willfully American to be persuaded by this duplicitous world I've been painting. Life's been better to me than most. The form I have gains a lot from its position in this system. Being an &lt;em&gt;Everyman&lt;/em&gt;, I can confidently tell you that power confers upon me. It's all encompassing and passive enough that I often miss it happening myself. You, dear reader, will never escape it or dismiss it with a privilege check. This power is indifferent to all of our perspectives. It often supersedes any point I intend to make as it's going to be the first thing that anyone not bestowed with it will interact with. To thrash against it is just as much a facade, concerning yourself with the optics of a position rather than holding it, and inspecting it does not seem to help from my anecdotal experience either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't say if this current feeling is guilt, whether it's labeled sufficiently as privilege, or if I will hand-wave it as survivorship bias in the future. Likely things started falling apart before I got here and it's just nature to thrash. I could pretend that this all has little bearing on what the future holds, but I've never found the nihilist's perspective. From where I'm at it seems I've personally been fucking up most of everything along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;I've Tried Nothing, Everything Works&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know these things, and I still feel like shit all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm more trying to construct a reason to clench my fists and rise above that is more concrete than innocent hopefulness. It's annoying to find myself again in this familiar old feeling, that depression is becoming my default. That depression is unremarkable and standardized. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey! That deeply personal struggle you have, with all its unique facets? Don't fret; everybody has it at some point. Come over here, and sit in the waiting room. Your therapist will have already printed out a spreadsheet with all of those pesky feelings little rows, ready to be checked. Once we are done here we can calculate what percentile you hit. Your very legitimate concerns with being unique might still ring true after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to play &lt;em&gt;Disco Elysum&lt;/em&gt; recently, it's one of the few pieces that felt like it understood me. If you haven't played it, you should. I won't spoil anything if you keep reading. But I want to highlight one of its perspectives on self harm and mental wellbeing. To make a long story short, a conclusion to the thought "Finger on the Eject Button" is spelled out in the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"...Turns out &lt;em&gt;Finger On The Eject Button&lt;/em&gt; is pretty much your theme song. A headbanger from your teenage years and your wedding ballad. This is not the first time you're spinning the tape." ~ Disco Elysium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know whether I will hold this perspective for long, but this take on depressiveness and suicidally feels right on the money. I feel it worth expressing that these topics are often put into media for the spectacle, and often do more harm in glorifying or sensationalizing self-harm. While I can't claim that Disco Elysum's quote is tactful, it feels far more genuine than most everything else I've come across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that the consistency of a depressive perspective is what gives it its power and weight. Whether my current perception is hopeful, longing, lustful, bliss, hatred, all the songs on the mixtape find there way back to dread. I imagine that most people when met with the call to the void instinctual head shake "no, no that's silly". That response is there, or rather, I know it should be. Instead my response seems to have always been:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Well, it's not really convenient for anyone right now. I know that ideas like 'deserve' are trite, and that no one 'deserves' to be alive. I just don't believe it... That I 'deserve' to be alive... It's just that now is not a good time, I got shit that I said I would do for some people, and well... Going through with this would mean lot of extra work for people, and the paperwork! Some people would be really sad if not annoyed... and I just don't want to push more of that shit into the universe right now..." and by that point I've found something to do with my hands or get hungry and leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;And after the fire, a soft murmuring sound&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I'm saying is that I have no triumphant retort to this soundtrack. I don't expect to defeat these feelings anymore. I know by now that breaking the fourth wall and asking you again if you are still reading is pointless. Even if I had the ability, I wouldn't want to know. I'm not pretending that I have some answer to these universals. I'm just hopeful that if you can tell that a real living feeling creature wrote this, that it's normal for things to be this painful. That, in spite of how weird and scary and fucking confusing all of these life questions actually are, we are always answering with something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These asides where I try and fail to distill a lifetime's worth of experience and emotion into some tangible nugget of truth always feels like risking a lot for very little. I have no expectations that anyone will vibe with any of this, and honestly, at this point, I'm accepting that it's fine to swear and be surly and show my soft white underbelly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darling, we have already failed at so many things, let's fail at our next endeavour.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="Musings"></category></entry><entry><title>Setting up GPG and Hardware Tokens</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/setting-up-gpg-and-hardware-tokens.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-07T12:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-09-07T12:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Shiddy</name></author><id>tag:shiddy.io,2020-09-07:/setting-up-gpg-and-hardware-tokens.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;GPG &amp;amp; Hardware Tokens&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://shiddy.io/images/Yubikey-Header.jpeg#headimg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Preamble"&gt;Preamble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Configuration"&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Our GPG key structure"&gt;Our GPG key structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Creating the Master Cert Key"&gt;Creating the Master Cert Key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Master Key Revocation"&gt;Master Key Revocation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Subkey Generation"&gt;Subkey Generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Exporting our keys"&gt;Exporting our keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Exporting Public Keys"&gt;Exporting Public Keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Exporting Private Keys"&gt;Exporting Private Keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Writing our Keys to a Yubikey"&gt;Writing our Keys to a Yubikey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#GPG Private Key Cleanup"&gt;GPG Private Key Cleanup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Publishing our Public GPG keys"&gt;Publishing our Public GPG keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Setting our SSH agent use our GPG keys"&gt;Setting our SSH agent …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;GPG &amp;amp; Hardware Tokens&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://shiddy.io/images/Yubikey-Header.jpeg#headimg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Preamble"&gt;Preamble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Configuration"&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Our GPG key structure"&gt;Our GPG key structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Creating the Master Cert Key"&gt;Creating the Master Cert Key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Master Key Revocation"&gt;Master Key Revocation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Subkey Generation"&gt;Subkey Generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Exporting our keys"&gt;Exporting our keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Exporting Public Keys"&gt;Exporting Public Keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Exporting Private Keys"&gt;Exporting Private Keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Writing our Keys to a Yubikey"&gt;Writing our Keys to a Yubikey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#GPG Private Key Cleanup"&gt;GPG Private Key Cleanup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Publishing our Public GPG keys"&gt;Publishing our Public GPG keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Setting our SSH agent use our GPG keys"&gt;Setting our SSH agent use our GPG keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Adding our public key to various authorized keys"&gt;Adding our public key to various authorized keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Setting touch behavior for Yubikey Subkeys"&gt;Setting touch behavior for Yubikey Subkeys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Setting pin retries for Yubikey"&gt;Setting pin retries for Yubikey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Setting pins for your Smart Card"&gt;Setting pins for your Smart Card&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#Enabling Disabling Yubikey features"&gt;Enabling/Disabling Yubikey features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Preamble"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Preamble&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I set up a new computer there is a fair amount of time spent on getting various configs into a state I am comfortable with. Unfortunately, I don't have a means to automatically set up hardware tokens for authing into some machines so I often have to spend a day just looking up all the various commands and parameters. This post aims to make that process easier for me in the future, but also hopefully save you some time on your next GPG key setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also am using the &lt;strong&gt;Yubikey 5&lt;/strong&gt; because &lt;a href="https://support.yubico.com/support/solutions/articles/15000027139-yubikey-5-2-3-enhancements-to-openpgp-3-4-support"&gt;it supports the GPG 3.4 Smart Card spec&lt;/a&gt;. Allowing us to write elliptic curve keypairs to the device. If you have a yubikey 4 or lower you will have to use RSA as your algorithm for all keys in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't claim to be a cryptography expert, and what I am posting here is to the best of my knowledge the most generic use-case friendly way to set up a hardware token. If you have improvements feel free to send me a PGP message with the details, or idk check my about page for where I am, I guess. (˵¯͒〰¯͒˵)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Requirements"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are ensuring we have three programs for the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPG - for creating and setting keys for smart-cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PinEntry - a utility that will pop up for our OS when we need to enter our smart card's pin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YkMan - a program that we can use to set the pins on our Yubikey, and require a human to touch it to authenticate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For MacOS I assume that you are using homebrew or are able to get these programs from valid sources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;gnupg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pinentry-mac&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;ykman
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Linux I am using a Debian based package manager, but I trust you are able to find these packages with your specific distro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;apt&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;scdaemon&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;libccid&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;yubikey-manager
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;pinentry&lt;/code&gt; requires you to know what kind of desktop environment you use on linux. For Ubuntu or Debian systems you would use "gnome", and install &lt;code&gt;pinentry-gnome3&lt;/code&gt;, etc... If you don't know I would recommend using pinentry-curses which should work with most ttys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id="Configuration"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to tell our gpg-agent what our pinentry program is as well as that we plan to use our GPG agent for ssh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires some directories to exist; the easiest way to ensure they exist is to use GPG itself to create them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-k
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;for MacOS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;which&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pinentry-curses&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;/dev/null&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
cat&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;pinentry-program $(which pinentry-curses)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;default-cache-ttl 3600&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;max-cache-ttl-ssh 3600&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;enable-ssh-support&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;verbose&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="s"&gt;log-file $(echo &amp;quot;$HOME/.gnupg/gpg-agent-log&amp;quot;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;EOF&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;You didn&amp;#39;t install the requirements, you should check the pinentry-mac install step above.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;```&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#### for Linux&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="sb"&gt;```&lt;/span&gt;bash
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-e&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;pinentry-program /usr/bin/pinentry\nenable-ssh-support&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$HOME&lt;/span&gt;/.gnupg/gpg-agnet.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Our GPG key structure"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Our GPG key structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we are working towards is a single GPG master key that certifies multiple subkeys for specific actions, namely: &lt;em&gt;Authorizing&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Signing&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Encrypting&lt;/em&gt;. When we talk about a key in this context, we are referring to a key-pair. Meaning, we will be making 8 keys in total 4 private and 4 public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;Master&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Certify&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Sub&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Signing&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Sub&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Encrypting&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="se"&gt;\-&lt;/span&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Sub&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Authorizing&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that there are mechanisms to run this as a batch job, however I want to walk through the steps manually first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id="Creating the Master Cert Key"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Creating the Master Cert Key&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--expert&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--full-generate-key&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--cert-digest-algo&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;H10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Note*&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;code&gt;--cert-digest-algo&lt;/code&gt; flag allows us to specify the hashing algorithm on these keys. By default we will see SHA256, which is fine for most everyone, but since we can specify SHA512 which will be faster on our 64-bit machines, and also generally help with security by making collisions with our hash much less likely, ヾ(´￢｀)ﾉ &lt;a href="https://www.gnupg.org/gph/en/manual/r2029.html"&gt;According to the Docs&lt;/a&gt; we can show the algorithms used here, but only some of them map to the globals in &lt;em&gt;gcrypt.h&lt;/em&gt; so no love on specifying whatever hash you want ¯\&lt;em&gt;(ツ)&lt;/em&gt;/¯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Note on note*&lt;/strong&gt; If you are so inclined, you can print the algorithms that GPG support with the following &lt;code&gt;gpg --vv --version&lt;/code&gt; this will show a specific identifier &lt;code&gt;H10&lt;/code&gt; in our case, which you can see points to SHA512.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-vv&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GPG key selection" src="https://shiddy.io/images/gpg-flags.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We select &lt;code&gt;(11) ECC (set your own capabilities&lt;/code&gt; and we then toggle the "signing" capability with the &lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt; key. Signing is on by default, we only the certify capability on this master key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GPG capability selection" src="https://shiddy.io/images/gpg-capability-selection.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we select &lt;code&gt;(Q) Finished&lt;/code&gt; to then specify the encryption algorithm. In our case we want &lt;code&gt;(1) Curve 25519&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we are prompted with how long we want this cert to be valid for. I normally don't like to set limits for how long a key will be used in fear that I will lose historical data. That being said, I also limit the damage that is done if these keys are compromised by creating a revocation certificate. So, I enter a &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; and confirm with &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; to state that my master key will not expire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we want to provide some information about who the key belongs to. I'll enter &lt;code&gt;shiddy&lt;/code&gt; for my name and &lt;code&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io&lt;/code&gt; for my email, and leave the comment blank. We then finalize the key creation with &lt;code&gt;(O)kay&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point you may be prompted for a passphrase, &lt;strong&gt;This is different than your smart card pin&lt;/strong&gt;, and is the only thing preventing this key from being used if someone gets access to your keyring or private key storage. Make sure to set it to something secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats! We now will follow a similar sequence of steps to generate our &lt;em&gt;Authorization&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Encryption&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Signing&lt;/em&gt; keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want to confirm our key status at any time we can execute &lt;code&gt;gpg --export shiddy@shiddy.io | gpg --list-packets&lt;/code&gt; On the off chance you don't know already, your email address is the identifier for your GPG key, so you will want to use your email from the previous step. Otherwise if you have one key at this point you can use the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--export&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-K&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;grep&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;lt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;cut&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-d&lt;span class="se"&gt;\&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-f2&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tr&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-d&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--list-packets
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; from here on out in the documentation I will only use my own key identifier. You should change this to have the same commands work on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shows that we have generated two keys &lt;code&gt;pkey[0]&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pkey[1]&lt;/code&gt; as part of the public packet, as well as our &lt;code&gt;digest algo 10&lt;/code&gt; as part of the signature packet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GPG list packets example" src="https://shiddy.io/images/gpg-list-packets-example.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id="Master Key Revocation"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Master Key Revocation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of being a good security minded individual, is making sure that we plan for the worst. Here we will make a revocation certificate to ensure that if we lose our private keys, we can just kill everything related to this key and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is important because we set this key to never expire, if our key was compromised we have no means of informing others. That being said, we also need to make sure that this revocation certificate is as secure as our Master secret key, otherwise anyone could revoke our keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--output&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy&lt;span class="se"&gt;\@&lt;/span&gt;shiddy.io.gpg-revocation-certificate&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--gen-revoke&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above command created a file &lt;code&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io.gpg-revocation-certificate&lt;/code&gt; which contains the revocation certificate, print it and put in in a fire-safe, slap it on a usb and put it somewhere safe but &lt;strong&gt;do not keep it on your hard drive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id="Subkey Generation"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Subkey Generation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to create our subkeys from our master Certify key. So we will tell GPG that we want to edit this key which will drop us into a GPG prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--expert&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--edit-key&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--cert-digest-algo&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;H10&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can then enter &lt;code&gt;addkey&lt;/code&gt; to begin the creation of a new subkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selecting &lt;code&gt;(11) ECC (set your own capabilities)&lt;/code&gt; again will default to &lt;em&gt;Sign&lt;/em&gt; as the only action, but we should confirm this and then Finalize our key selection with &lt;code&gt;(Q) Finished&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;(1) Curve 25519&lt;/code&gt; for the elliptic curve we want, that it will not expire with &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;, and a confirmation of &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two more to go! Let's create our &lt;em&gt;Authenticate&lt;/em&gt; key next&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invoke &lt;code&gt;addkey&lt;/code&gt; again, &lt;code&gt;(11) ECC (set your own capabilities)&lt;/code&gt; and this time only enabling the &lt;em&gt;Authorization&lt;/em&gt; capability and disabling any other capabilities (&lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; assuming the 'Sign' identifier is defaulted on your machine). &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; for the expiration date, and a confirmation with &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final &lt;code&gt;addkey&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;(12) ECC (encrypt only)&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;(1) Curve 25519&lt;/code&gt; for the elliptic curve, &lt;code&gt;Q&lt;/code&gt; to confirm the selection, &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; for the expiration date, and finally &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we want to cleanly exit GPG with &lt;code&gt;save&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! We now have a bunch of public and private keys attached to our Master Key!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we note what is returned to us here, we can see our master key set up with &lt;code&gt;sec ed25519&lt;/code&gt; and our &lt;em&gt;Sign&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Authenticate&lt;/em&gt; keys as &lt;code&gt;ssb ed25519&lt;/code&gt;. However our &lt;em&gt;Encryption&lt;/em&gt; key is a &lt;code&gt;ssb cv25519&lt;/code&gt; which specifies that it's going to be using an &lt;em&gt;integrated encryption scheme&lt;/em&gt; (IES) to encrypt since the plaintext that can be encrypted in most elliptic curves is much smaller than RSA at similar bit lengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also worth pointing out that we could create any subkey with any algorithm you desire, so if you for example worked at a place where it might not be guaranteed that you can ssh with elliptic curves, then you can reasonably only create the Authorization key as a RSA4096 while keeping the other two subkey pairs as EC25519. Dig?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can optionally add an image to this key with &lt;code&gt;addphoto&lt;/code&gt; but it's worth noting that this is going to be stored on other people's machines. Size is therefore a concern, if/when we put this on a cert server, we don't want to make the people offering free cryptography solutions sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id="Exporting our keys"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Exporting our keys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now ready to export our keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will export our secret keys we want to backup, as well as write to our smart card. We will also export our public keys, which we can publish to external hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a id="Exporting Public Keys"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Exporting Public Keys&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--export&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-a&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy&lt;span class="se"&gt;\@&lt;/span&gt;shiddy.io.pub
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a id="Exporting Private Keys"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Exporting Private Keys&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--export-secret-keys&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-a&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy&lt;span class="se"&gt;\@&lt;/span&gt;shiddy.io.priv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two export commands we ran created two files &lt;code&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io.pub&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io.priv&lt;/code&gt; we want to save the private file one in the same place as our &lt;code&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io.gpg-revocation-certificate&lt;/code&gt; from before. Making sure to remove them from the hard drive after doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we also now have our public key file. This should be &lt;strong&gt;super&lt;/strong&gt; public, put it in a place where you can use it. For example, This is one of the most used files on my NAS when I need to spin up new machines, since I want to make sure that I can access them from one well-known key. I suggest you do the same, put it out there keep some copies around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Writing our Keys to a Yubikey"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Writing our Keys to a Yubikey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's check that our computer is able to read the smart card data. After plugging in our card we can run &lt;code&gt;gpg --card-status&lt;/code&gt; to see what cards are plugged in, as well as what Signing, Encryption, and Authentication keys are on the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not starting out fresh, you can always run &lt;code&gt;ykman piv reset &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ykman openpgp reset&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;code&gt;ykman openpgp reset&lt;/code&gt; command resets your pin to '123456' and admin pin to '12345678'. We will see how those are used in the future, don't worry ( ﾟｰﾟ). It's assumed that you know your pin and admin pin. We will change it to something else later in &lt;a href="#Setting pins for your Smart Card"&gt;Setting pins for your Smart Card&lt;/a&gt; below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; if you find you are getting errors like &lt;code&gt;Error: Failed connecting to YubiKey ... Make sure the application has required permissions&lt;/code&gt; You might need to unplug and re-plug your hardware device. We are making many changes in the course of this post and sometimes it can lock after it's been updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--edit-key&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we want to select a specific subkey with &lt;code&gt;key 1&lt;/code&gt;. Doing so will mark the subkey with an asterisk &lt;strong&gt;(*)&lt;/strong&gt;. We then can send that specific key to our hardware token with &lt;code&gt;keytocard&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our key selected earlier was our signature key we inform the smart card it's a signature key with &lt;code&gt;(1) Signature Key&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GPG key selection" src="https://shiddy.io/images/gpg-key-selection.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tada!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can follow this pattern for our &lt;em&gt;Authentication&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Encryption&lt;/em&gt; subkeys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deselect our signature key with &lt;code&gt;key 1&lt;/code&gt;, select our Auth key with &lt;code&gt;key 2&lt;/code&gt;, apply it to the card with &lt;code&gt;keytocard&lt;/code&gt;, and tell the smart card it's an authentication key with &lt;code&gt;(2) Authentication Key&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GPG keytocard example" src="https://shiddy.io/images/gpg-keytocard-example.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we can write out our Encryption key. Deselect our authentication key with &lt;code&gt;key 2&lt;/code&gt;, select our encryption key with &lt;code&gt;key 3&lt;/code&gt;, write it to the card with &lt;code&gt;keytocard&lt;/code&gt;, and inform the card it's an encryption key with &lt;code&gt;(3) Encryption Key&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we cleanly close GPG with &lt;code&gt;save&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="GPG Private Key Cleanup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;GPG Private Key Cleanup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we have exported our Master key to a file, and we exported our Subkeys to our hardware device, we don't need GPG to know about or store any of our keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can confirm what public keys are installed with &lt;code&gt;gpg -k&lt;/code&gt;, and we can confirm what private keys are installed with &lt;code&gt;gpg -K&lt;/code&gt;. For now you should see both your private and public keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--delete-secret-and-public-keys&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy@shiddy.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to check that all your keys are gone with &lt;code&gt;gpg -K&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gpg -k&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will require a decent amount of confirming prompts, don't worry we already exported these keys. If worse comes to worse, this is a good time to fail and start over. Happens to the best of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will want to import our public keys to our GPG suite since it will be able to map them to the private keys on our smart card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--import&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;shiddy&lt;span class="se"&gt;\@&lt;/span&gt;shiddy.io.pub
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is a good time to confirm again what keys GPG know about, again &lt;code&gt;gpg -K&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gpg -k&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's confirm GPG knows that the public key we entered is related to the private keys on our card. We can be confirm this by running &lt;code&gt;gpg --card-status | tail&lt;/code&gt; and seeing whether the output is similar to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;sec#&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;ed25519&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;...
ssb&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;ed25519&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;...
ssb&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;ed25519&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;...
ssb&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;cv25519&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this tells us is that GPG has mapped some of the public keys we imported to private keys on this card. The &lt;strong&gt;sec#&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;ssb&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; inform us that GPG knows of a key but it does not have direct access to it. (Kinda like it's on our hardware key ৲(ᵕ3ᵕ)৴♡  )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Publishing our Public GPG keys"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Publishing our Public GPG keys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public keys are public... let's publish them! One such place where we can do so is on a keyserver. Here are some of the most common ones I've seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://keyserver.ubuntu.com/#
http://pgp.mit.edu/
https://keyserver.pgp.com/vkd/GetWelcomeScreen.event&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Setting our SSH agent use our GPG keys"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Setting our SSH agent use our GPG keys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I place a path variable in my .bashrc, however if you use another shell you might want to add it to it's appropriate profile/runcommand config. &lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt; Here be monsters, I spent a good ten minutes trying to get tmux and everything else happy. I'd stick with bashrc if you have the chance. &lt;a href="https://blog.flowblok.id.au/2013-02/shell-startup-scripts.html"&gt;[src]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-e&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;\nexport SSH_AUTH_SOCK=\&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;gpgconf&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--list-dirs&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;agent-ssh-socket&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;~/.bashrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;remember to source your new config as well &lt;code&gt;source ~/.bashrc&lt;/code&gt;, if you don't you will have to close and re-open your terminal for the key to be in your ssh agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id="Adding our public key to various authorized keys"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Adding our public key to various authorized keys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can print our public authentication key with the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh-add&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-L
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ssh-add -L example" src="https://shiddy.io/images/ssh-add-example.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which can then be added to any $HOME/.ssh/authorized_keys file on a server you want to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Setting touch behavior for Yubikey Subkeys"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Setting touch behavior for Yubikey Subkeys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are setting the state of the touch behavior for all our subkeys on our smart card. We have a few states to choose from.
If you would like to read more about them you can read them with &lt;code&gt;ykman openpgp keys set-touch -h&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you are doing any scripting where you would need to authenticate to a bunch of places over some reasonably small period of time, set your policy to &lt;code&gt;Cached&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;On&lt;/code&gt;, and if you don't want anyone to change this policy on your smart card, you can set &lt;code&gt;fixed&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;cached-fixed&lt;/code&gt; so that it can't be changed apart from a factory reset of the yubikey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;POLICY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;On&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;openpgp&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;keys&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;set-touch&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;SIG&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$POLICY&lt;/span&gt;
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;openpgp&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;keys&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;set-touch&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;AUT&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$POLICY&lt;/span&gt;
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;openpgp&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;keys&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;set-touch&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;ENC&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$POLICY&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Setting pin retries for Yubikey"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Setting pin retries for Yubikey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have some extra protections with our Yubikey that are worth enabling. Yubikey will lock out a key if a user fails to enter the correct password a number of times. However if you are like me and use a keyboard without any labels, you might want to make these thresholds more lenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I am setting the number of retries for my pin to 5, the number of reset-code retries to 5 and the number of admin-pin retries to 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;openpgp&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;access&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;set-retries&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id ="Setting pins for your Smart Card"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Setting pins for your Smart Card&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart Cards generally have two pins, a pin for regular verification of the card owner, and an admin pin for making hardware changes to the smart card itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we fail validation with the pin the number of times configured above, we have to use the administrative pin to unlock the key. If we fail to validate the admin key in the same way, we brick our key, and would have to factory reset it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can change these pins as well as unblock our pin with GPG, using the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--change-pin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have not modified this value yet, 123456 is the factory pin and 12345678 is the default administrative pin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id="Enabling Disabling Yubikey features"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Enabling/Disabling Yubikey features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like me are &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; interested in using these keys to back your GPG info, I would advise you to disable all of the yubikey features you are not using. Here is how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly we can check what kind of protocols are already configured/enabled on our device with the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;info
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my use case, it made sense for me to disable everything except PGP, which is done with the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;nfc&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--disable-all

ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;usb&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--disable&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;FIDO2
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;usb&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--disable&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;OTP
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;usb&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--disable&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;U2F
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;usb&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--disable&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;OATH
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;usb&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--disable&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;HSMAUTH
ykman&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;usb&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--disable&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;PIV
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ok. Bye&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( ・_・)ノ&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="Technical"></category></entry><entry><title>Turn-on Tune-in Burn-out</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/turn-on-tune-in-burn-out.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Shiddy</name></author><id>tag:shiddy.io,2017-09-09:/turn-on-tune-in-burn-out.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this at the peak of a burnout that has been lasting me for the better half of the last decade. I would like to think of myself as somewhat of an empiricist so I want to document what &lt;em&gt;this feels like&lt;/em&gt; and what this &lt;em&gt;felt like&lt;/em&gt; to determine …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this at the peak of a burnout that has been lasting me for the better half of the last decade. I would like to think of myself as somewhat of an empiricist so I want to document what &lt;em&gt;this feels like&lt;/em&gt; and what this &lt;em&gt;felt like&lt;/em&gt; to determine whether my decisions were worth it. Hopefully, those who read this can gain some insight before heading down the same road as I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will span a year; starting with my efforts throughout my senior year until I have finished with my Bachelor's degree and can provide my historical perspective on my work/life balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Crash and Burn:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Bleed like a Stone&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to appear as though I am not comfortable, nor in hard times. However I want to in some way document my thoughts on what burnout feels like, and my approach in handling it. It's not my intention to whine about non-issues. I am trying to eke out my reasons for feeling shitty with this blog post to document my recent outlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life is starting to feel like a looping version of a &lt;em&gt;National's&lt;/em&gt; album. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://i.imgur.com/p6yy011.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hear a lot of people expressing that they don't know what they want to do with their lives. I have been fortunate in being stubborn and figuring out what I wanted to do very early. I know that I wanted to work in computer security or R&amp;amp;D and I knew that I needed to get a degree to make it in those professions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll say it again: I am nervous to present my earnest feelings on how tired I am in these pursuits. I fear that a lot of you reading this may think, "What have you honestly done that would burn you out?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last five years, I have been working full-time and going to school full-time. Apart from my first year, I have not taken government money to pay tuition as I know there are others who need it more than me. From then on, I have paid for every penny of my higher education with money I have earned working. My work day starts around 8:00 am, and ends around 11:00 pm when I prepare for the next day. Personal work and leisure are for weekends when appropriate, or when not working on school/work related projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking my workplace's vacation hours. I have, over the course of the last five years taken twenty-eight days off work. twenty-one of which were school or work-related, meaning that I was working rather than relaxing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read through &lt;em&gt;Atlas Shrugged&lt;/em&gt; in my freshman year, and remember the protagonist Henry Rearden who was meant to symbolize the epitome of an objectivist. A person who was consistently productive and held himself in high esteem. He was always being told by everyone else to take a break. He persisted onward, applying intrinsic value to his work. For him, there was virtue in working through dedication and moral conviction. His worth was derived in its totality from the merits of his labor. I did, and still do, place a lot of value in being a productive and consistent person, not for productivity's sake; rather, because I find that people who are not doing interesting things are dreadful and boring. I hated conversations of pleasantry with people who didn't have new things to talk about or interesting thoughts of their own to share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was terrified of being boring. I found pleasure when other's would correct my enunciation, so I would not make the same mistake in other's company. I have always thrashed against my peers to try to speak affluently and be interesting. I consciously decided to exert time and effort pursuing things that would widen my perspective and change my thoughts rather than spend time doing things that I found interesting. I ate up (and still do to be completely honest) quotes like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you go home with somebody, and they don't have books, don't fuck 'em!” ― John Waters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite not being a particularly well-read person, that idea resonated with me to the point I would read things that I hated so that I could at least say that I have read them. It made sense to pursue a career in a field that is always changing and solves interesting problems. Doing things that people could tangibly see required great effort, whether spearheading or being part of something bold. It only made sense to quit my job as an electrician and pursue higher education to work with my brain rather than my back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without delving too far into the feelings that motivated me to dust off my blog and write about burnout and attrition. I think an image will suffice my current concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://i.imgur.com/O2YXXWT.png" width="100%" style="background-color: linen"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am only now realizing that I am not finding any new intrinsic value in my work or my schooling. Seeing this decline in interest in learning feels horrible. Often, the work that I am doing feels so far removed from what the outside world can see that I don't feel like there is any redeeming value in the work. I can't point to a web page or inform a friend that the thing he is doing with his phone was produced by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not the first time I have felt this, nor do I sincerely believe it will be the last. It is, however, the first time that I have felt this way since I had a glimpse of what I was aiming to do. I was for the first time able to see that my work was meaningful to someone and that it provided value. Weekends, where I would usually be able to suss out a couple hours of leisure after finishing my tasks, are now a marathon of guilt and dread. I can't even walk home from work on a Friday without immediately going over the work that I have to finish over the weekend so that I can have a "fresh" start to the week on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a constant anxiety that I used to only feel while procrastinating that has bled into every thought that I have, regardless if there is anything important that actually has to get done. Strangely, this feels like a real affliction based on artificial constraints. I don't believe that if I didn't accomplish every ridiculous goal that I have set the companies I would work for would fail. I don't think that if I suddenly stopped working that really anyone would feel a huge detriment to the business. If I quit school today I don't reasonably think that I would be in less of a position to succeed in my dreams. There are enough people doing all sorts of work around me that nothing of value would be lost if I popped out of existence today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why do I feel so stressed out and tired all the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels as though every waking second I have I should be working on doing something, anything so that I don't fall behind and lose everything. The more I earn the less I feel like any of it really matters. The proportional value I see when gaining something feels less than the thought of losing something of equal value that I already struggled for. I've taken a little time to look into why I feel this way and found there is at least some evidence that humans often place a higher value on what they have rather than what they could have. &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/BF00122574"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt; While this may only be anecdotal, I can't help but harken to a time where I had nothing to prove to anyone, the aimless summers when there were no black shrouds of guilt of not being productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't say that a large portion of my feelings regarding this has nothing to do with social adulation. I think that it would be easier to work on a more boring but required job if I was working for a company that was known well enough that my friends and family were familiar with a product my company provides. If I worked for Google, at least a grandparent could say "You remember Tell? The lanky one with the hair? He works for Google now." Rather than "You remember Tell? I hear he is doing well for himself with computer stuff." At least the brand awareness might make the process of reinventing the wheel more meaningful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I accept that a majority of the work that I am doing is important and that regardless of whether or not the work is glamorous or tedious, it remains a necessary step for building a company that can sustain itself. But I can't help but feel jaded at the fact that I am so muddled away in the background that even people who work in the same field as me have no idea what I do day to day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What burns the most is that after all is said and done, I hate that I have taken the skill that I have spent so long working to develop, and burned through every last bit of passion and joy I initially found in it. Recalling the days when I first thought to myself, "I can do this," where every lesson formed some piece of a cohesive whole. How every little improvement made a world of difference to how much fun it was to have to really think about what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when was first learning how to program with Scratch in high school. We were tasked with making a calculator with sprites that could do basic arithmetic up to three digits on the screen. As an incomprehensibly lazy child, paired with my rather unstudious nature, I knew that if I was to complete this assignment I would have to spend a lot of time to figure out how to do it. So I spent an entire evening working out how to make this program work. To my genuine astonishment, I was able to complete the assignment in a single night. I felt genuine satisfaction as began to unravel the complexities of something as simple as a calculator and know what little piece to add to the program next. It was such a novel concept at the time to use a variable to store a value of what I wanted to put on the screen, and that I could take the output of any calculation and update that same variable and have it all work itself out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I went to class, I remember being baffled that apart from one other student, the rest of my peers had attempted to hard-code hundreds of possibilities and ended up with programs like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;when 1 pressed:
  if + pressed
    if 1 pressed
      display 2
    if 2 pressed
      display 3
    ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember feeling so gratified when I was able to explain to them how I approached the problem with my variables. Watching them observe my thoughts and then have it "click" for them, jumping back to their computers to implement something simple rather than difficult. The rest of the day I was so excited to program the next assignment that I couldn't focus on any other classes. I was completely enamored with all the possibilities of things to make. I knew that if I tried hard enough that I could make anything with my computer, and I was so genuinely excited to learn what was next. I remember specifically thinking of what I would be doing once I got "good" at computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a lot of those dreams are within reach, and I can not be less interested. I get home, and you could not force me to do any projects "for fun." I don't want to listen to music, read, watch movies, or anything else to decompress; I just want to sit alone and not think about anything for once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike a lot of the anecdotal stories that I have read regarding burnout, I have documented a lot of what I have done in my daily journals and can review everything that I have experienced with more granularity. Since I have started working on new and interesting things, I have found that the majority of the entries are not positive, from my personal well-being and from my outlook on others. As much of a stoic as I see myself, there are a lot of people with whom I have either fallen out of favor or others who have fallen out of favor with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think that I have unintentionally burned many bridges with people, as the ebb and flow of life pulls people in as well as pushes them away. I can say, however, that the people with whom I have decided not to interact over the course of the last few years I have no intention of interacting with into the future. I have, through years of deliberate action, pruned those out of my life who I didn't think were helping add to the narrative of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entries in my journal from the earlier days were substantially less dramatic but were also a lot more innocent and hopeful. Here is a sample from a very old entry in my journal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... Not to imply that I am not constantly tired. Despite the constant shin splints and blisters, I will venture on, and hopefully, in time I can afford university and be somebody worth remembering. I want to live in a nice place, and spend time with people that are much smarter and more disciplined than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, was my bet worth it? Do I feel more satisfied than before? Would I do it again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with anything qualitative worth writing about, the answer lies in a gradient of yesses and nos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Happiness &amp;amp; Other Illogical Nonsense.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would argue that for the majority of time since the dawn of humanity people have spent the majority of their efforts singly focused on one question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Can I always be happy? Is there a way to ensure that happiness is my default state of being?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I, or anyone else who has looked at this question honestly, the answer is a resounding &lt;em&gt;No&lt;/em&gt;. There are at current count, 7.5 billion humans on this planet, all of whom have different goals and motivations. For the entirety of human history, no two single people can look at each other's actions and motivations and come to a complete consensus as to what the purpose of life is. There is no valid reasoning as to why no person can consistently act in accordance with that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not even comparable to any other human endeavor. It is the subconscious goal of every being on this planet to find or accept some extrinsic reason to do anything. It's why I'm writing, and why you're reading. People have locked themselves away in caves, endured extreme hardships, fasted, and writhed to perhaps glean meaning and happiness. Yet, no one has come any closer to any conclusive answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be the equivalent if every single person was a scientist focusing every waking moment to determining whether or not &lt;em&gt;fire bad&lt;/em&gt; and still coming up with wildly different assertions today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't honestly believe that there is any true satisfaction that comes from anything intrinsic in the universe. I understand but do not like the fact that I have accepted that this is the case. That it is easier to be happy when distracted. I believe that my value and meaning in life comes only from what I personally decide to attribute meaning to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is a person like me to do? I want to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone I care about shared the following video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yWkq7btSQvs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading through my journals over the last years I have realized something. That the points where I was most happy or interested in working, I was working towards something. I only now realize that as my degree is coming to an end, and I have achieved my dream job, I don't have any particular goals that I am working toward. I guess I didn't think that I would have gotten this far by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that I have spent enough time here waxing non-poetic about burnout. But I need to start knowing what the goals in the next chapter in my life should look like.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="Musings"></category></entry><entry><title>The Curse of the Gifted</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/Pay%20it%20forward...%20technically.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Shiddy</name></author><id>tag:shiddy.io,2016-03-05:/Pay it forward... technically.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;In college, I studied comp-sci
in class, so damned bored I could die.
convinced to be best
showed up for the test
Turns out all my skills were a lie.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this venture, I am almost done with my university education. No matter where you stand on higher education, I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;In college, I studied comp-sci
in class, so damned bored I could die.
convinced to be best
showed up for the test
Turns out all my skills were a lie.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this venture, I am almost done with my university education. No matter where you stand on higher education, I personally found that the experience was worth all the cost, time, and effort in one revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am not awesome, I am ungrateful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to avoid self-deprecation here. What I mean by that is that I have changed my perspective on my abilities and more importantly the way that I have to approach problems in my life. Up to the last few years of college, I believed that things should be a meritocracy. I only wanted to be judged by the abilities I had. Nothing else should be taken into account for one's ability to progress in life. And although I still feel that in an idealized world this might be something that is worth implementing, I am finding that I would most likely end up in a position that I would not enjoy. Moreover, I think that most people would find themselves unhappy, uneducated and unfulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These conclusions mostly stem from recent conversations that I regret looking back on. The times when someone would tell me, in the most sincere and kind way possible, that I needed to stop treating others like they don't have anything to offer me. Nothing cuts you down quite as much as being told you're an asshole by someone you know and trust, especially when you know that they have nothing but your best interest at heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Social Network&lt;/em&gt; (despite its portrayal of Mark Zuckerberg at the end of the film) explains this elegantly in the opening scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"...You're going to go through life thinking that girls don't like you because you're a nerd. And I want you to know, from the bottom of my heart, that that won't be true. It'll be because you're an asshole."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth of the matter is that for the first time in my life I am beginning to realize that I have been that asshole. There have been countless times that I have lied about things I don't fully understand to people that were not trying to prove anything. There have been even more times when I have assumed that because someone does not know as much as me, or since they don't understand something quite as quickly as I do, that they should study more, work harder, or that they are trying to subvert actually learning by leaching what I felt I had learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you catch that? I &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; that I had done something. Feelings are often deceptive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="https://xkcd.com/610/" src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sheeple.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think that I am some hard-working Henry Reardon, but in reality, I've really only ever been a B student. I've never truly known what it was like to try hard because the effort that I would have to exert to get an A would be more than I am honestly willing to spend. I don't know what it's like to try hard at something because most things tend to click early enough for me that I don't really worry about doing well, it tends to just happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limerick at the top of this post I wrote after I got my first calculus 2 test. I had gotten a 54%. Despite never really trying in the course and getting a B as a final grade, I still think about that. I failed at something. What surprised me more than my grade, however, was that people I knew around me had done much better than I. As I put my red ink soaked paper in the back of my notebook, I remember responding to a classmate that \"I did fine\" after he had asked. A few days later I found &lt;a href="https://www.vanadac.com/~dajhorn/novelties/ESR%20-%20Curse%20Of%20The%20Gifted.html"&gt;a wonderful article by Eric S. Raymond&lt;/a&gt;, wherein some of the problems I had hit were being discussed from an outside perspective. ESR called it \"the curse of the gifted\" and defines it as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"A tendency to lean on your native ability too much, because you've always been rewarded for doing that and self-discipline would take actual work."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know if I am at this point, and to be honest the uncharted territory of being poor at something makes me hope that I never do. In the same breath, however, I know that I am not as nearly as amazing as most of the brilliant people I work with, study with, and spend time with, I am sure that a fair bit of them might feel the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most influential people in my life was a high school English teacher that tried to instill in me the process of \"paying it forward.\" Reciprocating the gifts others had given me that I didn't really deserve. Real people, that write answers to others in forums, make how to guides, write books and take the time to share their insights to the world without seeking social adulation or fame. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus far I have really only abused the system. I have a bookshelf overflowing with technical books that I have sought out and purchased because their insights have moved me. In them, I have gained knowledge that I deceptively tout to be my own, while the real authors deserve far more praise than I. The countless articles and manuals that I have read on tools and processes written by people that didn't even bother to pen their name to the content they were providing staggers me. People that took literal man hours to help foster knowledge in others whom they didn't know. I am not an island, and all of my success in life can be directly attributed to those who paid it forward to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to think that when someone does not get something immediately or struggles with something I find easy, that they should simply try harder. But if I was to sum up all the hours that I had wracked my brain on a problem I find easy now, I guarantee that I would think I was a complete imbecile. Therefore, it's purely ego. I have no idea how many people I have unintentionally prevented from getting into technology because of my ego. And now that I see that in myself, I don't want to propagate my harmful outlook in others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we as a group ever want computer science to be loved by others, we need to call out people like me for not paying it forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="Musings"></category></entry><entry><title>Phone Marketing Nonsense</title><link href="https://shiddy.io/phone-marketing-nonsense.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2015-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Shiddy</name></author><id>tag:shiddy.io,2015-08-05:/phone-marketing-nonsense.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;I don't want a new phone.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't. I love my phone despite all its flaws. All of which are completely my fault and are not in any way the manufacturers. My phone has lasted through a personal hell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hours underwater when I went swimming on vacation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being left …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;I don't want a new phone.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't. I love my phone despite all its flaws. All of which are completely my fault and are not in any way the manufacturers. My phone has lasted through a personal hell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hours underwater when I went swimming on vacation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being left in a snow bank for a few days when I had to hitchhike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being dropped to the point the metal corners bent inward. (the screen is still flawless)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The back camera has been broken after being punctured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently taped over with duct tape, both cameras only show red when active.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The battery lasts around 6 hours after a full charge with no usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the final straw for my pocket buddy was that HTC decided it was a good idea to start placing advertisements in the push notifications. Absolutely unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my quest to find a decent phone I wanted to document some of the nonsense I've seen. I was expecting fad features. I'm looking at you “OK, Google”… and don't think I forgot about you Mr “break me on anything galaxy edge”. Instead, I found that the marketing for cell phones the most confusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being cognizant of cellphone hardware no longer is a concern for an average consumer. Most phones work amazingly well. Even mediocre phones do more than an average person has time to enjoy. Distinguishing yourself as a manufacturer to your potential consumers is more akin to a popularity contest than ever. Yet, I find myself subject to less consumer vitriol online as well. Apart from short interest spikes after a release, announcements and product news does not seem to last more than a day. Keeping customers engaged with your service appears to be the holy grail of phone manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This can be seen most clearly with Apple and OnePlus.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need not speak of the marketing pull Apple has on the first world. They market their products as sleek, and fashionable status symbol. People have the perception that Apple iPhones are the most powerful, and are involved with the most designing effort of any modern day cell phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was certainly the case at the launch of the iPhone. The cell phone design paradigm was seemingly set in stone by Apple. Josh Heifferich's image of phones before and after Apple got involved does the most justice to prove this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://shiddy.io/images/150805-phone.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Digeratii/status/165324320179109888"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Screen Size&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Storage&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Removable Storage&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Memory&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Battery&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Camera (rear)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Camera (front)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Apple iPhone 6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;5.5”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;16GB&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1GB LPDDR3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2915mAh&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;8MP&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1.2MP&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;$749 usd&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Samsung Galaxy S5&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;5.1”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;16Gb&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2GB LPDDR3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2800mAh&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;16MP&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2MP&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;~$410 usd&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-iphone/iphone6/5.5-inch-display-16gb-silver"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-SM-G900H-Unlocked-Cellphone-International/dp/B00JKSUHLU/ref=sr_1_1"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;CPU&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Cores&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Clock Speed&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;CL1Cashe (Data)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Architecture&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Apple A8&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1.4 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;64Kb/Core&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Harvard&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;SnapDragon 805&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2.7 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;16Kb/Core&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Harvard&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes Apple so ubiquitous is clearly it's advertising and word of mouth. They have built a reputation of having the highest quality phones used by the most famous people. As of my typing of this, they sell a watch for $17,000. Which is only $7,000 difference between their cheapest gold watch. The price difference is due entirely to a watchband color.
I don't want to spend time berating those who want to own these devices, nor spend space on my server dissecting why we are willing to pay more for status. Apple is the most clear example of how marketing is he most important factor in the success of mobile consumer technology, and sets the bar pretty high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Which brings me to OnePlus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OnePlus is an attempt to build a company identity that has failed in all the right ways. Most people are not aware that this company is owned by Oppo Electronics. I as most others believed that the company was akin to a startup or scaling company. According to most press at the time of their launch the general consensus was that this company was a small group built on creating high-end mobile products at ridiculously cheap prices. I managed to find an article I read a couple years ago after first hearing about the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For years, building a smartphone was only a possibility for the biggest of tech companies, but more and more small manufacturers have begun throwing their hats in the ring — from Jolla, to Blu Products, to Yota Devices. OnePlus is the latest in that ilk of small manufacturers” 
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/12/16/5217794/oppo-ex-vice-president-pete-lau-launches-oneplus"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that I put much stock in the Verge, but this understanding was rather prevalent throughout my following of OnePlus. There is a world of difference between “small manufacturers” and a subsidiary of Oppo electronics. Regardless of the intent, or the relativism of the word “small” defining their business, this attempt to change public perception worked. Therefore, their marketing pitch of overthrowing the status quo as a small new manufacturer was alluring to most of the hipsters (myself included)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then rolled in the invites… If you want to purchase a OnePlus 2 (silly name aside) you have to sign up to be on a waiting list which automatically increases your queue placement based on how many referrals you generate. These referrals are generated through getting others to sign up and join the queue as well. It does not matter whether you were signed up first, it matters that you have more referrals than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://media.giphy.com/media/7wToiGB3M5wME/giphy.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think that it's reasonable to toady your potential customers around the way that the marketing team for OnePlus demands in order for you to buy their products. I'm absolutely anti-spam and anti-solicitation. Their invite system will artificially force people abusing the system or spamming to the top of the queue. This is not even that hard for people to accomplish anymore. &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@JakeCooper/how-i-hacked-the-oneplus-reservation-system-120ea1a7ad82"&gt;There are articles showing how it's possible and has been done already.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evangelical marketing schemes like what OnePlus has implemented uproot the trust that we have in communally identifying worthwhile products. This is the most upsetting because the OnePlus 1 &amp;amp; 2 are more than powerful enough to get started through grass roots and word of mouth legitimately. I would own one already if it were not for their marketing bogus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a good bit of advice for people who think this is not all that bad. If you are told that you have to tell other people how good something is before you can own it, it's probably not a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's rather unfortunate that I'm beginning to have to play detective for company selling anything to see whether it's a giant marketing ploy…&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="Random"></category></entry></feed>